Ali Seyhun Saral

Email: saral@coll.mpg.de | Web: www.saral.it

ABOUT

Current Affiliation: Max Planck Institute for Research on Collective Goods, Bonn, Germany

Research Intererests: Cooperation, Behavioral and Experimental Economics, Game Theory,

Evolutionary Game Theory, Agent-Based Modelling,

Social Preferences, Social Production, Social Choice Theory

Side Interests: Methodology of Experimental Economics, Software Development,

Open-Science, Free/Open-Source Software, Science Communication

EDUCATION

2014 - 2019 Trento University, PhD in Economics And Management

Dissertation: "Three Essays on Cooperation and Reciprocity"

Supervisors: Luciano Andreozzi, Matteo Ploner

2010 - 2012 Istanbul Bilgi University, MSc in Economics

Dissertation: "Group Polarization on Altruistic Behavior"

Supervisor: Ayça Ebru Giritligil

2006-2010 Istanbul University, BA in Economics, Minor in Philosophy

EMPLOYMENT

2020 - ongoing Max Planck Institute for Research on Collective Goods

Postdoctoral Researcher (part-time), Experimental Economics Group

PI: Matthias Sutter

2018 - ongoing Max Planck Institute for Research on Collective Goods

Lab Manager

2017 Trento University

Teaching Assistant

2012 - 2014 Istanbul Bilgi University

Teaching Assistant

Lab Manager

PUBLICATIONS

- Andreozzi, L., Ploner, M., **Saral, A. S.*** (2020). The stability of conditional cooperation: beliefs alone cannot explain the decline of cooperation in social dilemmas. *Scientific Reports* 10, 13610.
- Saral, A. S.*, & Schröter, A. M. (2019). zBrac—A multilanguage tool for z-Tree. Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Finance, 23, 59-63.

WORK IN PROGRESS

- Reciprocity in Dictator Games (with Luciano Andreozzi and Marco Faillo)
- The Evolution of Conditional Cooperation in Prisoner's Dilemma

Working paper: https://osf.io/wcpkz/

- Reciprocity, Conformity and the Evolution of Human Cooperation (with Angelo Romano)
- Social Production: Voluntary Provision of Information Goods (with Annika Hennes)
- Generating representatives from Anonymously and Neutrally Equivalent Classes (ANEC): An algorithm to enumerate root profiles (with Jochen Staudacher, Sebastian Kaunzinger and Fatma Aslan)

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Game Theory Trento University (T.A.), (2017) Istanbul Bilgi University (T.A.) (2012)

Intermediate Microeconomics Istanbul Bilgi University (T.A.) (2012-2013)

Advanced Microeconomics Istanbul Bilgi University (T.A.) (2013)

Introduction To Economics Istanbul Bilgi University (T.A.) (2012-2013)

Experiments with z-Tree Istanbul Bilgi University (2010-2014, 2016)

Ca' Foscari University (2017)

Max Planck Institute for Research Collective Goods (2018)

Experiments with oTree Max Planck Institute for Research on Collective Goods (2019-2020)

Data Visualization in R JDMx Workshop, Trento (2019)

^{*} Corresponding author

• ESA European Meeting (Cologne 2012, Vienna 2017, Dijon 2019) • Conference on Economic Design, Istanbul (2015) • Florence-Constance joint Workshop on Behavioural and Experimental Social Sciences (2017) • Venice Doctoral Workshop on Economics And Management (2017) • 11th IMPRS Uncertaininty Workshop, Trento (2017) • Seminar, University of Erfurt (2019)

OTHER RELEVANT TRAINING

• Internship at Istanbul Stock Exchange (2010) • Internship at the Experimental Economics Lab of Siena University, LabSi (2012) • CNRS Summer School on Interdisciplinary Analysis of Voting Rules, Caen (2012) • IMPRS Uncertainity Summer School, Jena (2016) • Summer School on Computational Social Choice, San Sebastian (2016) • Behavioral Game Theory Summer School, Norwich (2019) • Integrating Open Source Communities in Corporate Environments Micro-Course, Brandeis University (2020)

AWARDS & FELLOWSHIPS

Istanbul Bilgi University, MSc. Program, Tuition & Fee Waiver (70%) (2010)

Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey, Graduate Fellowship (2010-2012)

Trento University, PhD. Fellowship (2014-2018)

Computer Skills

My computer skills include but not limited to statistical analysis, data mining, software development, experimental software, web development, servers and networks.

Experimental Economics z-Tree, oTree

 $\begin{array}{lll} \textbf{Mathemathics \& Statistics} & R, \, Stata, \, SPSS, \, MATLAB \\ \textbf{General Purpose} & Python, \, C/C++, \, Lisp \\ \end{array}$

Web Development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Django, Bootstrap, PHP

Visual Design

Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Inscape, TikZ

Misc.

IATEX, Mathematica, Biopac Systems, Linux,

Network & Server management, Apache, Git, SQL

References

Luciano Andreozzi < luciano.andreozzi@coll.mpg.de> University of Trento, Italy.

Christoph Engel <engel@coll.mpg.de>
Max Planck Institute for Research on Collective Goods, Bonn, Germany.

Ayca Ebru Giritligil <ayca.ebru@bilgi.edu.tr>
Istanbul Bilqi University, Turkey.

Matteo Ploner <matteo.ploner@unitn.it> University of Trento, Italy.

Matthias Sutter <matthias.sutter@coll.mpg.de>
Max Planck Institute for Research on Collective Goods, Bonn, Germany.